A forbidden love. An unthinkable attraction. The ultimate price.
Lolita is a drama, romance film directed by Adrian Lyne.
Humbert Humbert is a middle-aged British novelist who is both appalled
by and attracted to the vulgarity of American culture.
When he comes to stay at the boarding house run by Charlotte Haze, he soon
becomes obsessed with Lolita, the woman's teenaged daughter.
Humbert Humbert, played by Jeremy Irons.
Dolores "Lolita" Haze, played by Dominique Swain.
Charlotte Haze, played by Melanie Griffith.
Clare Quilty, played by Frank Langella.
Miss Pratt, played by Suzanne Shepherd.
Reverend Rigger, played by Keith Reddin.
Lolita is a 1997 drama film directed by Adrian
Lyne and written by Stephen Schiff.
It is the second screen adaptation of Vladimir Nabokov's 1955 novel of the same name and stars Jeremy Irons as Humbert Humbert and Dominique
Swain as Dolores "Lolita" Haze, with supporting roles by Melanie Griffith as Charlotte Haze and Frank Langella as Clare Quilty.
The film is about a middle-aged professor who is sexually
attracted to adolescent girls he calls "nymphets".
He rents a room in the house of a young widow to get closer to her
14-year-old daughter Dolores Haze "Lo", whom he calls "Lolita".
Obsessed with the girl, he eventually gains control over her
after he takes her cross-country with him.
Compared to Stanley Kubrick's 1962 version, Lyne's film is more overt with many of the novel's
darker elements; Kubrick chose to use suggestion and innuendo for comic purposes.
Although praised by some critics for its faithfulness to Nabokov's narrative and the performances of
Irons and Swain, the film received a mixed critical reception in the United States.
The film premiered in Europe in 1997 before being released in the United States in
1998 because it had difficulty finding an American distributor.
It was eventually picked up by the cable network Showtime before finally
being released theatrically by The Samuel Goldwyn Company.
Similarly, Lolita was met with much controversy in Australia, where it
was not given a theatrical release until April 1999.
The film explores themes of jealousy, based on novel
or book, police, obsession, professor.
The tone is emotional.